<recipes>
    <recipe>
        <name>Collard Green Pie</name>
        <category>Main Course</category>
        <ingredients>
            <crust>
                <ingredient>1 1/2 cups flour</ingredient>
                <ingredient>1/4 tsp salt</ingredient>
                <ingredient>4 tbsp butter</ingredient>
                <ingredient>1/4 cup oil (pref. safflower)</ingredient>
                <ingredient>Enough water to form a ball</ingredient>
            </crust>
            <filling>
                <ingredient>1 onion</ingredient>
                <ingredient>2 cups Collard Greens</ingredient>
                <ingredient>1 large egg or two medium eggs</ingredient>
                <ingredient>1/2 tsp salt</ingredient>
                <ingredient>1/2 cup grated Asiago or Parmesan cheese</ingredient>
            </filling>
        </ingredients>
        <directions>
            <crust>
                <direction>Stir together flour and salt.  Cut in butter until only
                fine balls appear.</direction>
                <direction>Cut in oil until evenly distributed.</direction>
                <direction>Pour in water and form dough into ball.  Roll out and
                put into pan.  Poke holes in bottom of crust.</direction>
            </crust>
            <filling>
                <direction>Put Collard Greens in food processor until finely chopped
                (a bit coarser than pesto).</direction>
                <direction>Chop onion and saute until golden brown.</direction>
                <direction>Combine Collard Greens, onion, egg, salt, and half the
                cheese.  Pour into crust.</direction>
                <direction>Grate remaining cheese on pie.</direction>
            </filling>
            <baking>
                <direction>Bake on 425F for 15 minutes.  Turn down to 375F and bake
                for another 30 minutes.</direction>
                <direction>To check if done:  Check if crust is golden brown and
                poke knife into filling.  The knife should come out clean.</direction>
            </baking>
        </directions>
    </recipe>
    <recipe>
        <name>Pizza</name>
        <category>Main Course</category>
        <ingredients>
            <serving-size>This recipe serves four people, with some leftovers.</serving-size>
            <crust>
                <ingredient>1 cup water or milk, heated (the dough will rise more with milk)</ingredient>
                <ingredient>1 large egg</ingredient>
                <ingredient>2 tbsp olive oil (this is optional, but it tastes much better)</ingredient>
                <ingredient>2 tbsp sugar (in my experience, honey will make the dough rise best)</ingredient>
                <ingredient>3 cups flour</ingredient>
                <ingredient>2.5 tbsp yeast</ingredient>
                <ingredient>1 tbsp herbs (we use Frozen Pizza seasoning or Bouquet Garni)</ingredient>
                <ingredient>1 tsp salt</ingredient>
            </crust>
            <topping>
                <ingredient>Pasta sauce (however much you like)</ingredient>
                <ingredient>Shredded mozzarella cheese (again, however much you like)</ingredient>
                <ingredient>Assorted vegetables and herbs, to taste</ingredient>
            </topping>
        </ingredients>
        <directions>
            <crust>
                <direction>If you're using a breadmaker, let the breadmaker stir the
                pizza until the ball is fully kneaded.  Pull the dough ball out before
                it rises in the container (we'll do this in the pizza pan instead).</direction>
                <direction>If you're not using a breadmaker, follow the directions below:</direction>
                <d>Mix the salt, herbs, and flower together well in a large bowl.</d>
                <d>In a separate bowl, I like to use a medium-sized soup bowl, mix the
                water or milk, sugar, and yeast together, and let the yeast puff up (it
                should take 15-20 minutes, but if your yeast is more active and starts
                going over the edge of your bowl, feel free to continue sooner).</d>
                <d>Stir the egg and oil into the flour mixture until it's even.</d>
                <d>Preheat the oven to 350ºF (this way, there's enough time for it
                to heat fully before the dough needs to rise).</d>
                <d>Once the yeast is ready, combine the yeast starter mixture into
                the flour mixture, kneading until it's well-combined.  The dough should
                be even, with no lumps, and silky.</d>
                <d>Divide the crust into four even parts and stretch into whatever shape
                pie pan you have.  Pretty much any pans work, though we tend to use
                9x13 inch glass pans, pie pans, and 8x8 glass pans the most.</d>
                <d>Place the dough in the oven for 2-3 minutes, until the pans are
                hot, but not too hot to touch.  Let the dough rise for 15-20 minutes,
                or until it's doubled in size.  Once it's ready, you can begin
                assembling the filling on top of it.</d>
            </crust>
            <topping>
                <direction>Pour pasta/marinara sauce on top the pizzas, spreading it
                with a spoon.  It's up to you how much sauce you like on your pizza.</direction>
                <direction>Sprinkle grated mozzarella cheese on top of the pizzas evenly.</direction>
                <direction>Add vegetables to your liking.  I like to slice onions and
                peppers thinly, then stir fry them until soft on the stove.  This way,
                the onions caramelize in the oven.  If you decide to add greens, I
                recommend putting them under the cheese in the pizza sauce, and you
                may want to cut them up a bit.  For tomatoes, they're great on pizza,
                but make sure you cut them at least in half.  Otherwise, they cook
                weird and when you bite in, they're far more likely to burn you.</direction>
            </topping>
            <baking>
                <direction>Bake on 375ºF for 18 minutes.</direction>
                <direction>To check if your pizzas are done:  Check if the crust
                is golden brown on the bottom, and make sure the cheese is slightly
                browned on the top (if it gets too brown, it gets really hard to
                chew, so if there's any question whether the cheese is done, take
                the pizzas out).</direction>
            </baking>
        </directions>
    </recipe>
    <recipe>
        <name>Spinach Soup</name>
        <category>Soup</category>
        <ingredients>
            <ingredient>Spinach</ingredient>
            <ingredient>Coconut milk</ingredient>
            <coconut-milk-notes>
                <note>Don't use Xanthum Gum</note>
                <note>Use one with Guar Gum</note>
            </coconut-milk-notes>
        </ingredients>
    </recipe>
</recipes>